<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>chapliboy</title>
    <link>https://www.chapliboy.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on chapliboy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.chapliboy.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The UX of Puzzle Games</title>
      <link>https://www.chapliboy.com/ux_of_puzzle_games/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 06:49:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.chapliboy.com/ux_of_puzzle_games/</guid>
      <description>Every aspect of a game has an impact on the players experience.
I developed a puzzle game, and learnt a lot over the course of that journey.. It&amp;rsquo;s out on Steam now.
So here&amp;rsquo;s the subtle aspects of puzzle game design.
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Idea to Steam</title>
      <link>https://www.chapliboy.com/journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 06:49:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.chapliboy.com/journey/</guid>
      <description>I just released Konkan Coast Pirate Solutions.
It is a cozy puzzle game about helping pirate ships do pirate things. It&amp;rsquo;s out on Steam now.
So here&amp;rsquo;s how I the game evolved from the initial idea.
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing an Artstyle</title>
      <link>https://www.chapliboy.com/artstyle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2023 06:49:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.chapliboy.com/artstyle/</guid>
      <description>The first thing you see of a game is a visual. A gif on reddit, a clip on tiktok. Some snippet of some video essay. A thumbnail on steam. And if they&amp;rsquo;re on your steam page, the trailer and screenshots better not disappoint&amp;hellip; that&amp;rsquo;s what decides if you&amp;rsquo;re getting a wishlist. That&amp;rsquo;s just how it goes&amp;hellip;
So when it came to my game, It was challenge I would face at some point or the other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Game in a Custom Engine</title>
      <link>https://www.chapliboy.com/custom-engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 06:49:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.chapliboy.com/custom-engine/</guid>
      <description>Using a custom engine to create a game is sometimes discouraged. People highlight a whole host of reasons why it is a bad idea. So I thought I could talk a bit about some reasons why it is a good idea. Or atleast, why it was a good idea for me.
I used a custom engine to develop Konkan Coast Pirate Solutions.
It is a cozy puzzle game about helping pirate ships do pirate things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle Games and Difficulty</title>
      <link>https://www.chapliboy.com/puzzles-and-difficulty/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 06:49:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.chapliboy.com/puzzles-and-difficulty/</guid>
      <description>I love Stephen Sausage Roll.
It was the first puzzle game that I played, and it will always be the gold standard for me. It was brutally difficult at times. Just manoeuvring around the levels can be difficult, and my playthrough spread out over more than a year. I would face a difficult puzzle, break my head over it for a while, and be completely stuck. Then I would take a long break.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>